Young Master
少爷
Aying
阿英
Slower
慢点
Ah Ying, how is your injury?
阿莹，你的伤怎么样了？
Don't worry, sir, I'm fine
别担心，先生，我很好
It's just a skin injury
这只是皮外伤
It's you
是你
Seriously injured
严重受伤
Come and drink the medicine first
先来喝药吧
Drink quickly
快点喝
Ah Ying, my injury doesn't matter
阿莹，我的伤并不重要
Let's quickly rendezvous with the army
赶快与军队会合吧
How about going back to Yingzhou?
回瀛州怎么样？
no
不
Young Master's injuries
少爷的伤势
I've already asked Taozi
我已经问过桃子了
And those healers?
还有那些治疗师呢？
they all said
他们都说
Be sure to do well
一定要做好
take some rest
休息一下
Aying
阿英
Just to recuperate
只是为了恢复体力
You can't recuperate here either.
你也不能在这里恢复。
look
看
This is where the Zhenxi Army is located
这里是镇西军所在地
Li Yi detained you and me again
李易又扣押你我
I'm afraid he has a plan
我担心他有计划
The current situation in Yingzhou
瀛州现状
Very critical
非常关键
You know
你知道
The Zhenxi Army took Luoyang by itself
镇西军独取洛阳
He already holds half of the mountains and rivers in his hands
他手中已握有半壁江山
He has a problem with our Cui Jiajun again
他又和我们崔家俊有问题了
I'm afraid of him
我怕他
The Zhenxi Army will not act like this
镇西军不会这样
Do you think Zhenxi Army
你认为镇西军
Not so
并非如此
I still think Li Yi would not be like this
我还是觉得李毅不会这样
Sun Jing has not been eliminated
孙静没有被淘汰
The Zhenxi Army is also the division of King Qin
镇西军也是秦王的师
anyway
反正
Neither can the Zhenxi Army
镇西军也不能
To our Cui Jiajun
To our Cui Jiajun
Act like this
这样做
Sun Jing is in danger
孙静遇到危险
All the passes have been lost, the passes have been broken
所有的通行证都已丢失，通行证已被破坏
His army of one hundred thousand
他的十万大军
Conquering Baiyue in the south again
再次南征百越
Li Yiruo points his sword at West Changjing
李一若剑指西长靖
Sun Jing, in addition to sticking to his
孙静除了坚守自己的
no other way
别无退路
He only has the forbidden army now
他现在只有禁军
Li Yiruo captured Xichangjing
Li Yiruo captured Xichangjing
Until then
直到那时
Just to take your head and mine
只是为了夺走你和我的头
to coerce father
胁迫父亲
Coercing Cui Jiajun
Coercing Cui Jiajun
Young Master is worrying too much
少爷担心太多了
Don’t say that Xichangjing is now
别说现在是西昌京了
Impregnable
坚不可摧
Even if one day
哪怕有一天
Li Ni captured Xichangjing
Li Ni captured Xichangjing
Neither will he
他也不会
How does it treat our Cui Jiajun?
它是如何对待我们的崔家俊的？
Are you being raped by Li Yi?
你是不是被李毅强暴了？
Drink the ecstasy soup
喝迷魂汤
Do you
你
To put Cui Jiajun’s safety at risk
危及崔家俊的安全
Disregarding his father's safety
不顾父亲的安危
So determined
于是下定决心
to be gullible
容易受骗
A frivolous villain?
一个轻浮的恶棍？
Young Master
少爷
I'm talking about things
我正在谈论事情
Aying
阿英
The young master’s injury has not healed yet
少爷的伤还没好
It’s better to meditate and recuperate
最好是冥想和恢复
Aying Aying
阿英阿英
Gongzi Gongzi
Gongzi Gongzi
school lieutenant
学校中尉
Although this secret medicine is extremely good
这秘药虽然极好
But you still have to pay attention to your wound
但还是要注意伤口
Be sure to avoid food
一定要避免食物
Otherwise you will leave scars
不然会留下疤痕
Okay, got it
好，知道了
Very good
非常好
Why do you have to climb through the window to get in?
为什么要爬窗才能进去？
When I just came in
我刚进来的时候
Met Taozi
与桃子
She doesn't let me bring outside food
她不让我带外面的食物
So I had no choice but to climb through the window
所以我没办法只能从窗户爬进去
Look what I have prepared for you
看看我为你准备了什么
grand grandson
孙子
I thought it was some kind of treasure
我以为这是某种宝藏
Just a few pancakes
只需几块煎饼
Actually
实际上
And a bowl of meat
还有一碗肉
I want you to eat a burrito
我要你吃墨西哥卷饼
But I was outside the window just now
但我刚才在窗外
I heard Taozi say that you should avoid food
我听桃子说你要忌口
Can't eat meat
不能吃肉
So I ate the meat
于是我就吃了肉
Just make do with it for you
就为你凑合一下
Have a piece of cake
吃一块蛋糕
What's so strange about this cake?
这蛋糕有什么奇怪的？
It’s worth bringing to Emperor Sunba Baba
值得带给孙巴巴巴皇帝
Not surprising at all
一点也不奇怪
I just know you have a poor appetite
我只知道你胃口不好
Branded especially for you
专为您打造的品牌
Since I can’t eat meat
因为我不能吃肉
Then dip it in some honey and eat it
然后沾点蜂蜜吃
This is rare
这是罕见的
Where does this honey come from?
这种蜂蜜从哪里来？
Afternoon
下午
I'm on the mountainside under a rock
我在山腰的一块岩石下
Found a beehive
发现了一个蜂箱
So I told Lao Bao
于是我告诉老包
Go and pick it off
去把它摘下来
This bowl of honey
这碗蜂蜜
Enough to feed you for several days
够你吃几天的
You need to take medicine to recover from your injuries
你需要吃药才能恢复伤势
If it’s hard to take medicine
如果吃药有困难
Just drink it with honey.
只要和蜂蜜一起喝就可以了。
correct
正确的
I have something to ask you
我有事想问你
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I will tell you everything
我会告诉你一切
Nothing to say
无话可说
Emperor's grandson
皇帝的孙子
How do you plan to regain West Changjing?
打算如何收复西长泾？
if i tell you
如果我告诉你
I'm at a loss
我不知所措
Do you believe it or not?
你信不信？
I believe it
我相信这个
If it were me
如果是我的话
I will also be at a loss
我也会不知所措
Western Kyoto, Kyoto
京都西京都
Taizu conquered one hundred thousand people
太祖征伐十万人
Sixteen years of construction
十六年建设
Impregnable
坚不可摧
Sun Jing
Sun Jing
Famous generals in the world
世界著名将军
He once conquered Gaoji three times
曾三征高吉
His ability to defend the city
他有保卫城市的能力
It's much more powerful than our siege.
比我们的围攻威力还要大得多。
Not to mention siege
更不用说围攻了
It is much more difficult than defending the city.
这比守城要困难得多。
and
和
Sun Jing is a cold and cruel person
孙靖是一个冷酷残忍的人
almost invulnerable
几乎无懈可击
you say
你说
Can I not be helpless?
我能不无奈吗？
Now he sends a large army to fight against Baiyue
现在他派出大军去讨伐百越
They also sent a large group of troops north to Yingzhou.
他们还派出大队北上颍州。
actually
实际上
He doesn't have many soldiers at his disposal
他手下没有多少士兵可供调遣
There are also 100,000 forbidden troops
还有十万禁军
Keep it for defending the city.
保留它以保卫城市。
Imperial Guard
帝国卫队
Originally the teacher of the emperor's personal general
原本是皇帝贴身将军的老师
Can it be shaken?
可以动摇吗？
It was the Imperial Guard who rebelled in the first place.
最先叛变的是禁军。
Otherwise Sun Jing
否则孙静
Able to rely on one's own strength
能够依靠自己的力量
Subvert Chao Gang and kill the late emperor
颠覆朝纲，杀先帝
Kill the kings?
杀死国王？
Trapped and surrounded
被困并被包围
trapped and surrounded
被困和包围
This is a plan
这是一个计划
Now Sun Jing is hoarding food again
现在孙静又开始囤粮了
To prepare for siege
为攻城做准备
A city like Xichangjing
A city like Xichangjing
Even if it lasts a year and a half
哪怕持续一年半
It’s not necessarily possible to break the city.
攻破城池也不一定。
At that time
当时
Sun Jing is sure
孙静确定
The army that conquered Baiyue has been recalled
攻克百越的军队已被召回
Let's attack from both front and back
让我们从正面和背面进攻
Even if we join forces then
就算我们联手
You may not be able to win this round
您可能无法赢得这一轮
What if
如果什么
I have a plan
我有个计划
Can break the city
能破城
Is the emperor's grandson willing?
皇孙愿意吗？
Promise me something
答应我一件事
are you willing to stay
你愿意留下来吗
Join me in defeating West Changjing
跟我一起打败西长靖
Do you want to surround Wei and save Zhao?
你想围魏救赵吗？
To relieve Yingzhou's difficulties, right?
是为了解除瀛州的困难吧？
If we can break West Changjing
若能攻破西长靖
Or force Sun Jing to
或者逼迫孙静
Those who were besieged in Yingzhou
被围困瀛州的人
Return troops and horses
归还兵马
The siege of Nayingzhou was solved
那英州之围被解
I promise you
我答应你
Even if you tell me ten thousand things
就算你告诉我一万件事
I can promise you anything
我可以向你保证任何事
The emperor's grandson is really
真是皇帝孙子啊
Only seeing the immediate benefits
只看到眼前的利益
If I can't break the city
如果我不能摧毁这座城市
Then you
然后你
You can't promise me anything anymore
你不能再向我承诺任何事
That's not true
这不是真的
If you can't break the city
如果你不能摧毁这座城市
I can promise you
我可以向你保证
Nine thousand nine hundred and ninety-nine things
九千九百九十九件事
But you have to promise me one thing
但你必须答应我一件事
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Haven't thought about it yet
还没想好
Wait until I think about it
等我考虑一下
It's not too late if you promise me again
如果你再答应我一次还不算太晚
Why such a weird statement?
为什么会有这样奇怪的说法？
I always feel
我总觉得
what are you planning
你打算做什么
do not worry
不用担心
I won't let Lieutenant He
我不会让何中尉
You are in trouble
你有麻烦了
What about me?
关于我的什么？
I won't make it difficult for you either
我也不会为难你
Saburo
三郎
The scouts found out
球探发现
Cui Lin and He
崔琳与何
After being rescued by Li Yi
被李毅救下后
Recuperating in Aoguan
在奥关疗养
It was hard to fake it
很难伪造它
Secret letter from uncle who is ill
生病的叔叔的密信
Also Cui Lin and He's family
还有崔琳和何家人
Defraud the Chinese Army
欺骗中国军队
Want to kill in one fell swoop
想要一击毙命
Who knew that Li Yi would appear?
谁知道李毅会出现？
Now the two of them are hiding in Auguan
现在两人就躲在奥关
There's nothing we can do
我们无能为力
Hello Li Ni
你好李妮
Ruined my good deeds again
又毁了我的好事
Sanlang, don't worry
三郎别担心
Cui Lin and He's soldiers and horses
崔霖和何氏兵马
Not much left
所剩无几
The Cui family's army was also blocked on the way
崔家大军也在途中受阻
It's impossible for them
对他们来说这是不可能的
Stayed in Aoguan
住在奥关
As long as we wait patiently
只要我们耐心等待
You can always find an opportunity to strike again
你总能找到再次出击的机会
Send me orders
向我发送订单
Set up camp near Aoguan
在奥关附近扎营
besides
除了
Let the scouts investigate closely
让球探仔细调查
Cui Lin and the whereabouts of the He family
崔琳与何家的下落
Once the two of them leave Aoguan,
两人一离开奥关，
That's when they die
那是他们死的时候
yes
是的
Young Master
少爷
You might as well
你还不如
You might as well get a knife
你还不如拿把刀
kill me
杀了我
you listen to me
你听我说
If we can fight with the Zhenxi Army
如果能和镇西军战斗的话
Let’s break the city together
让我们一起打破这座城市
The siege of Yingzhou will be lifted immediately
瀛州之围将立即解除
The Zhenxi Army cannot be trusted gullibly
镇西军不可轻信
Moreover
而且
Besides, West Changjing
另外，西长泾
Once someone knows your identity
一旦有人知道你的身份
What a dangerous thing that is
这是多么危险的事情
Young Master
少爷
Sun Jing has always been a traitor in the world
孙靖一直是世间的奸臣
But he is arrogant
但他很傲慢
He would never have thought that Li Yi and I
他万万没想到，我和李毅
Dare to sneak into Xichangjing alone?
敢独自潜入西场京？
That's not allowed
这是不允许的
just in case
万一
If there is an emergency in Xichangjing
如果西场泾有紧急情况
The siege of Yingzhou must be lifted
瀛州之围必须解除
If this is a game of Zhenlong
如果这是真龙的游戏
Then this move is the chess move.
那么这一步棋就是棋步。
Don't say anything
什么也别说
I won't let you go
我不会让你走
The young master cares about Yingzhou
少爷关心瀛州
But I'm worried about my safety
但我担心我的安全
But I've decided to go
但我已经决定去
Sir, don’t worry
先生，别担心？？
Even if things are not harmonious
即使事情不和谐
I will definitely be able to return safely
我一定能平安回来
Aying
阿英
I plead
我恳求
can you not go
你能不走吗
Young master me
少爷我
Ah Ying, I'm really worried about you
阿莹，我真的很担心你
If you are
如果你是
If you were trapped in West Changjing
如果你被困在西长泾
How do you want me to see my handsome father?
你想让我怎样见到我英俊的父亲？
if you are true
如果你是真的
Lost in West Changjing
迷失西长泾
I will never redeem myself
我永远不会救赎自己
Young Master
少爷
I've made up my mind
我决定了
Ah Shu, take good care of the young master
阿舒，照顾好少爷
Aying
阿英
Young Master
少爷
You might as well get a knife
你还不如拿把刀
Kill me now
现在杀了我
Keep me out of sight
让我看不见
Not that much
没有那么多
OK OK
好的好的
You just told me
你刚刚告诉我
Are you planning to go with He?
你打算和他一起去吗？
Disguised and sneaked into Xichangjing
乔装潜入西场京
Plan to seize the city
计划夺取城市
yes
是的
Are you still right with me?
你还和我在一起吗？
OK
好的
I'm going to find the rope now
我现在就去找绳子
I tied myself up
我把自己绑了起来
I don’t need my father to ask me
我不需要我父亲来问我
I asked him myself
我亲自问他
Go and ask for forgiveness
去请求原谅
I'll go now
我现在就去
wrong
错误的
I should tie you up
我应该把你绑起来
Send them back to the rear camp of the Zhenxi Army
送回镇西军后营
Arrived at father's place
到达父亲住处
Even if you want to overturn the world
就算你想颠覆世界
It's none of my business anymore
这不再是我的事了
General Pei's rear camp
裴将军后营
Thousands of miles away from here
距离这里数千里
As long as you don't say
只要你不说
He won't know
他不会知道
What's the rush?
急什么？
Jushichiro
十七郎
Think about it yourself
你自己想想吧
You are now the coach of Zhenxi Army
你现在是镇西军主帅
You and He
你和他
unarmed
徒手
I'm going to go to West Changjing
我要去长靖西
If someone by Sun Jing
孙静的《如果有人》
Found it
找到了
That's the wolf entering the tiger's mouth
这就是狼入虎口
You will never come back
你永远不会回来
Who said there are only two of us?
谁说只有我们两个人？
I also plan to take Lao Bao with me
我也打算带老包一起去
And long ears
还有长耳朵
Who said we were bare-handed?
谁说我们赤手空拳？
We will definitely carry weapons.
我们肯定会携带武器。
Don't tell me this
别告诉我这个
Anyway, I won't allow you to go
无论如何，我不会让你走
If you are worried
如果您担心
Come with us
跟我们来
I can't even go
我什至不能去
right
正确的
you can't go
你不能走
We need you to guard Aoguan here.
我们这里需要你守护奥关。
Just stay here
就待在这里
Wait for my good news
等我的好消息
OK OK OK
好好好
After sneaking into Xichangjing
潜入西场泾后
what's your plan
你的计划是什么
What are your plans?
你的计划是什么？
No plan, act by ear
没有计划，见机行事
What
什么
lied to you
对你撒谎了
Don't worry, I must have a plan
别担心，我一定有计划
Even if something happens
就算发生什么事
I will also look for opportunities to escape
我也会寻找机会逃跑
But we need you here in Aoguan
但奥关我们需要你
Stay here
待在这
Don't worry about the rest
其余的不用担心
do you know
你知道吗
if you get stuck in
如果你陷入困境
words from xichangjing
西场经的话
I have no choice at all
我根本没有选择
save you
拯救你
They will definitely take you by then
到时候他们肯定会带你去
Threaten the entire Zhenxi Army
威胁整个镇西军
That's natural
那是自然的
do not worry
不用担心
What if I really
如果我真的
Caught by Sun Jing
被孙静抓住
I've thought about it for you
我已经替你想好了
Just say that you have been disobedient for a long time
就说你已经不听话了
If you kill me
如果你杀了我
You, Pei, will definitely proclaim himself emperor to thank you.
裴氏你一定会称帝谢罪的。
I promise
我保证
Sun Jing will definitely be angry to death
孙静肯定会气死的
Sun Jing is not mad at you
孙静没生你的气
I'm already mad at you
我已经生你的气了
Your Majesty, your Royal Highness is here.
陛下，殿下来了。
Met the emperor's grandson
见到了皇帝的孙子
Miss Gu is too polite
顾小姐太客气了
Qiucui, pour the tea quickly
秋翠，快倒茶吧
Miss Gu is here this time
顾小姐这次来了
one thing
一件事
I want to ask Miss Gu
我想问问顾小姐
Your Majesty is welcome
欢迎陛下
If there is a destiny, do whatever you want
如果有缘分，就去做你想做的事
Gu Xiang is in Beijing
Gu Xiang is in Beijing
I would like to invite Miss Gu
我想邀请顾小姐
Give me a token
给我一个令牌
I want to send people to Beijing
我要派人去北京
Discuss with Xiang Gu to regain West Changjing
与项姑商议收复西长靖
Things that should be coordinated inside and outside
内外应协调的事情
If there is no token
如果没有令牌
I'm afraid it's hard to win Prime Minister Gu's trust
恐怕很难赢得顾总理的信任
The emperor and grandson want to send people to Beijing
皇孙要派人进京
He must be a confidant
他一定是知己
That being the case
既然如此
No need for any tokens
不需要任何代币
Wan Niang is willing to go there in person
万娘愿意亲自去一趟
No
不
Going to see Prime Minister Gu is already a helpless move
去见顾总理已经是无奈之举
Miss Gu can no longer be put in danger
顾小姐不能再陷入危险了
The emperor and his grandson help the world
皇帝与孙子济世
Now take back West Changjing
现在夺回西长泾
Everyone is responsible
每个人都有责任
Although Wan Niang is a prostitute,
万娘虽是妓女，
I am also willing to contribute to the great cause of the world
我也愿意为世界的伟大事业贡献一份力量
Try your best
尽你所能
My father is loyal to the country
我的父亲忠于国家
I have been suffering for a long time
我已经痛苦了很长一段时间
No matter what the emperor's grandson has planned
不管皇孙有什么打算
My father will definitely help me
我爸爸一定会帮助我的
Infiltration into Nishichokyo
渗入西町京
Once discovered
一旦发现
It will be dangerous
会很危险
The emperor's grandson will definitely let Brother Xie
皇孙一定会让谢兄
Brother Bao and others enter Beijing
包哥等人进京
They are all battle-hardened
他们都是身经百战的
A witty and brave person
一个机智勇敢的人
Wan Niang pretends to be a family member
万娘假扮家人
It's no problem
没问题
Just in case something goes wrong
以防万一出现问题
Wan Niang will commit suicide
万娘会自杀
Never bring anyone down
永远不要让任何人失望
I have tasted this wine
我尝过这款酒
The aroma of wine overflows
酒香四溢
really not bad
真的不错
This wine is from Luzhou
此酒产自泸州
Why travel thousands of miles?
为何要长途跋涉？
Ship it to Xichangjing
运送至西场泾
my master
我的主人
There is a wine shop in Beijing
北京有一家酒肆
Business has not been good these past two years
这两年生意不太好
The master is old
师傅老了
Convenience young master
方便少爷
Personally escort the wine to Beijing
亲自护送酒到北京
Stop by the wine shop to check the bill
去酒店检查账单
My young lady
我的小姐
My natal family was originally in Beijing
我的原生家庭在北京
Follow me to Beijing this time
这次跟我去北京
Go back to your parents’ home to visit your elders
回到父母身边？？？回家探望长辈
Jushichiro
十七郎
This was well planned beforehand
这是事先计划好的
Only Captain He
唯有何队长
One person pretends to be a female dependent
一个人假装是一名女性家属
Now suddenly there is one more
现在突然多了一个
Miss Gu
顾小姐
Then what should I say?
那我该怎么说呢？
I can only say she is my sister.
我只能说她是我妹妹。
What about Miss Gu going there?
顾小姐去那里怎么样？
Have you told Lieutenant He?
你告诉何中尉了吗？
said
说
Miss Gu
顾小姐
What about pretending to be your sister?
冒充你妹妹怎么样？
You also told Captain He
你还告诉何队长
said
说
Then Lieutenant He didn't say anything else.
然后何中尉就没有再说什么。
She actually said
她其实说
You can also pretend to be her sister
你也可以假装成她的妹妹
It’s just that I think it’s disguised as
只是我认为它伪装成
Aren’t everyone’s sisters the same?
每个人的姐妹不都一样吗？
It’s really different
真的不一样
You
你
Hurry up and let Miss Gu
赶紧让顾小姐
Let’s pretend to be Captain He’s sister
咱们假装是何队长的妹妹吧
Lieutenant He, you are going too
何中尉，你也去吧
Yes
是的
Huang Sun said
黄孙说
Miss Gu took the initiative to ask for help
顾小姐主动寻求帮助
It's admirable
令人敬佩的是
This is the right thing to do
这是正确的做法
Lieutenant He is overly praised
何中尉受到过分赞扬
You and I pretend to be sisters
你我假装是姐妹
Don’t worry too much on the road
路上不用太担心
Just play it by ear
见机行事
Ready to go
准备好出发
Will the emperor and his grandson also ride with us?
皇上和他的孙子也会和我们一起骑行吗？
No need, I'll ride a horse
不用了，我去骑马
Excuse me, you two, take the car.
对不起，你们两个，开车吧。
A Niang
A Niang
Our food
我们的食物
Finally enough to collect and store food
终于够收集和储存食物了
otherwise
否则
I still don’t know that I was killed by the military master
我还不知道我被军师杀了
Why are you in trouble?
你为什么有麻烦？
Fortunately
幸运的是
I told you to Xu Jia Sanlang
I told you to Xu Jia Sanlang
There's an order to stock up on food in this city.
有命令要在这座城市里储备食物。
Lady Xu
徐夫人
Send someone with a message immediately
立即向某人发送消息
He said he had prepared food for us
他说他已经为我们准备了食物
Still talking
还在说话
If it weren't for Xu Sanlang
如果不是许三郎
Went to Tuzhou to sell cloth.
去土州卖布。
I'm afraid I'll have to let Saburo take the food
恐怕我得让三郎拿食物了
Send it to the city for us
帮我们寄到城市
Madam Xu is so interested in you
徐女士对你很感兴趣
You will definitely be a loving mother-in-law in the future
将来你一定会是一个慈爱的婆婆
A Niang
A Niang
Qiniang
Qiniang
A sergeant is coming
一名中士来了
Lady Xu said
徐女士说
People sent by Governor Sun Da
孙达省长派人
Grabbing food everywhere
到处抢食物
What should I do
我应该怎么办
How do you cover this?
你如何涵盖这个？
Where to hide?
躲到哪里去？
Come and get my mother's clothes
快来给妈妈拿衣服
Come quickly
快来
Hurry this way
快点往这边走
There's someone in front of you guys
有人在你们前面
well
出色地
Go, go, go
去！去！去
Hurry up, hurry up
快点快点
Miss Gu, just ask whatever you want to ask.
顾小姐，你想问什么就问吧。
Is the poison on the arrow in your sleeve quenched with poison?
你袖中箭上的毒是不是被毒药淬灭了？
poisonous
有毒
But there is an antidote
但有解药
Wan Niang is just curious
万娘只是好奇
Captain He is a girl
何队长是个女孩
Naturally there are many inconveniences in the military
军队里自然也有很多不便
But heroic
但英勇
Calm and free
平静而自由
how to do it
怎么做
What is a person like in person?
一个人本身是什么样的？
Covering up cannot be covered up
掩盖是掩盖不了的
That's how I was originally
我原本就是这样的
undisguised
毫不掩饰的
Naturally, he is free and easy
自然是洒脱的
Everything in the world
世界上的一切
Want something
想要一些东西
Nature will also be trapped by it
大自然也会被它困住
Miss Gu is a smart person
顾小姐是个聪明人
I definitely understand
我绝对明白
Thanks to Lieutenant He for his advice.
感谢何中尉的建议。
Spare us
饶了我们吧
please
请
don't want
不想要
A Niang
A Niang
What's wrong
怎么了
There's a lot ahead
前面还有很多事
Someone is shouting for help
有人大声呼救
Spare us
饶了我们吧
please
请
A Niang A Niang
A Niang A Niang
Auntie, please wake up.
阿姨，你醒醒吧。
Smelly bitches
臭母狗
A Niang
A Niang
For a few bags of broken food
为了几袋破碎的食物
You dare to bite me
你竟然敢咬我
I won’t treat you today
我今天不会招待你
Chop it into pieces and feed it to the wolves
砍成碎片喂狼
It’s hard to understand the hatred in my heart
心里的恨意难以理解
Who?
WHO？
Your grandpa and I are here
我和你爷爷在这里
Take a slap from grandpa
挨爷爷一巴掌
Auntie, please wake up
阿姨，你醒醒吧
A Niang
A Niang
Auntie, wake up
阿姨，醒醒吧
It turned out to be Sun Jing's subordinate
原来是孙静的部下
No wonder he's so cruel
难怪他这么残忍
Either robbery or murder
要么是抢劫，要么是谋杀
A Niang
A Niang
Auntie, wake up
阿姨，醒醒吧
A Niang A Niang
A Niang A Niang
Mom, are you awake?
妈妈，你醒了吗？
A Niang
A Niang
Auntie, are you okay?
阿姨，你还好吗？
right
正确的
These are the martyrs
这些是烈士
Passing by saved us
路过救了我们
Thank you to all the martyrs for saving lives.
感谢所有拯救生命的烈士。
Auntie, you're welcome
阿姨，不客气
We were passing by too
我们也路过
Drawing a sword to help when the road is rough
路途坎坷，拔剑相助
Those people are too bad
那些人太坏了
Not just stealing your stuff
不只是偷你的东西
Killing innocent people indiscriminately
滥杀无辜
Those are all sergeants.
这些都是中士。
I'm afraid there will be trouble
我怕会有麻烦
All righteous men, please leave quickly.
各位正义之士，请速速离开。
Say it then
那就说吧
They say my old woman is crazy
他们说我的老太婆疯了
Just wounded the sergeant
刚刚打伤了中士
Grandma is fine
奶奶很好
Those bad guys are dead
那些坏人都死了
The martyrs buried them all
烈士们把他们全部埋葬了
They also spread grass on it
他们还在上面铺了草
Auntie is fine
阿姨很好
Just don't worry
不用担心
To save the old woman and the little girl
为了救老太婆和小女孩
Killed the sergeant
杀了中士
If it is known to outsiders
如果被外人知道
But I will be sent away by the official
但我会被官方送走
Catch Lingchi
抓灵池
Auntie, don't worry
阿姨别担心
If you don’t say it, we won’t say it.
如果你不说，我们就不会说。
No one will know
没有人会知道
Auntie, it's getting late
阿姨，时间不早了
Take the little lady home quickly
赶紧带小女人回家吧
A few righteous men
几个正义之士
Please pay homage to the old woman
请大家瞻仰这位老妇人
No, no, no, get up quickly
不不不，快点起来
Get up quickly, Auntie
快点起来阿姨
A few righteous men
几个正义之士
That car is full of food
那辆车里装满了食物
The righteous man saved the lives of our mother and daughter
正义之士救了我们母女的命
I'll give those grains to you.
我会把那些谷物给你。
No, thank you, auntie
不用了，谢谢阿姨
We always bring dry food with us when we go out
我们外出时总是随身携带干粮
You go to the city quickly
你快点去城里
If it's later, you won't be able to get in.
如果再晚的话就进不去了。
Come to Aniang
来阿娘吧
Then thank you all the martyrs
然后感谢所有烈士
life-saving grace
拯救生命的恩典
Thank you, martyr
谢谢你，烈士
Miss Six
六小姐
Why are you back?
你怎么回来了？
Hard to describe in one word
很难一言以蔽之
Go and inform your father quickly
赶紧去通知你父亲
Miss Six
六小姐
Prime Minister is not feeling well today
首相今天身体不舒服
Don't dare to disturb me at this time
这个时候不敢打扰我
I have something urgent
我有急事
If it's delayed
如果延迟的话
Can you afford it?
你买得起吗？
What can Miss Six have?
六小姐能有什么？
It's important
这一点很重要
I went to Bingzhou to pay homage to my father’s ancestors
我去并州祭拜我父亲的祖先
Come back in a hurry
赶紧回来
There must be something important
一定有什么重要的事情
you a slave
你是个奴隶
Block me out
阻止我
No notification
无通知
according to family rules
根据家庭规则
Being perfunctory and contemptuous of the master
敷衍、蔑视主人
what crime do you deserve
你该受什么罪
This sixth lady used to be a boring gourd
这六小姐以前就是个无聊的葫芦
Why did you suddenly become so powerful today?
怎么今天突然变得这么厉害了？
Miss Six is ​​serious
六小姐是认真的吗？？？？
Miss Six, please come in quickly.
六小姐，请快进来。
I'll pass it on right away
我马上转达
you mean
你的意思是
Seventeen emperors and grandsons sent capable people
十七帝孙派能人
hope to meet me
希望见到我
My daughter has been in Zhenxi Army recently
我女儿最近在镇西军
seen it myself
我自己看过
The seventeenth emperor's grandson was open-minded and generous.
十七皇孙为人豁达大度。
Able to conquer and fight well
善于征服，善于战斗
Everyone in Zhenxi Army admired him
镇西军人人都佩服他
Now the emperor's grandson can go down to Aoguan
现在皇孙可以下奥关了
Half of the country is under control
半个国家已被控制
what the people want
人民想要什么
Xichangjing is also in the bag
西昌井也收入囊中
Although Sun Jing was brave for a while,
孙靖虽然一时勇敢，
It’s just sitting in sleepy city
它只是坐在沉睡的城市里
Wan Niang
Wan Niang
You used to be in front of your father
你曾经在你父亲面前
But I've never spoken like this
但我从来没有这样说过
never said
从未说过
So many words
这么多话
You used to belong to the imperial court
你曾经属于朝廷
Taiping Xiangguo
Taiping Xiangguo
then be your daughter
那就做你的女儿吧
It's naturally different from now
自然和现在不一样了
What's the difference?
有什么不同？
What do you think
你怎么认为
Be the daughter of the Prime Minister of Taiping
是太平天国宰相的女儿
Just obey your parents
只要听从父母的话
Honor your relatives, care for your siblings
孝敬亲人，关心兄弟姐妹
I usually spend time admiring flowers and enjoying the moon
我通常花时间赏花赏月
Just listen to music and recite poems
就听听音乐，背诵诗歌
What about now?
现在呢？
Father, you are in prison for Sun Jing
父亲，你是为了孙靖入狱的
Still unyielding
依然不屈
Many aristocratic families in Beijing take you as a role model
北京很多世家都以你为榜样
Even the emperor and grandson mentioned you
连皇孙都提到你
It’s also full of admiration
也是充满了敬佩
Be your daughter now
现在做你的女儿
Know how to understand the current situation
懂得如何了解现状
Understand the general trend of the world
了解世界大势
Tell your father everything you know
告诉你父亲你所知道的一切
Nothing to say
无话可说
If the father feels
如果父亲觉得
My little daughter
我的小女儿
Still slightly usable
还是稍微有点用的
Then Wan Niang was satisfied
然后万娘就满足了
Wan Niang
Wan Niang
once upon a time father
从前 父亲
I misjudged you
我误判你了
Father is worried about state affairs
父亲忧国事
Pays little attention to family affairs
很少关心家庭事务
Otherwise, with my father’s discerning eyes,
不然的话，以我父亲雪亮的眼睛，
How can you say that you saw it wrong?
你怎么能说你看错了呢？
Then tell me about it
然后告诉我这件事
These seventeen emperors and grandsons sent people to see me
这十七个皇孙派人来见我
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Wan Niang apologizes to her father
万娘向父亲道歉
Just now Wan Niang deceived her father
刚才万娘欺骗了她的父亲
In fact, the seventeenth emperor's grandson
事实上，十七皇帝的孙子
Didn't they send people here?
他们不是派人过来的吗？
But he came by himself
但他自己来了
I want to interview my father
我想采访我的父亲
Miss Gu
顾小姐
Met the emperor's grandson
见到了皇帝的孙子
Miss Gu is too polite
顾小姐太客气了
Invite me here
邀请我来这里
But Mr. Gu agreed to meet him
但顾先生同意见面
yes
是的
After Wan Niang returns home
万娘回家后
Explained to father
向父亲解释
The emperor's grandson has entered the city
皇孙进城了
Father is very happy
父亲很高兴
I just want to come and see the emperor’s grandson in person right away
我只是想马上过来见见皇帝的孙子
But after my father was released from prison
但父亲出狱后
Sun Jing has been sending people to monitor closely
孙静一直在派人严密监视
Although my father can occasionally leave the house,
虽然父亲偶尔可以离开家，
But there are always eyeliners following you
但总有眼线跟着你
The government doesn’t even know how to arrange it
政府都不知道怎么安排
How much eyeliner is there?
眼线笔有多少？
Wan Niang pretended to go out of town today to offer incense
万娘今日假装出城上香
Specially invite the emperor’s grandson
特意请皇帝的孙子
I also asked the emperor and his grandson to come up with some ideas.
还请皇上和他的孙子出点主意。
How can I get my father to get rid of the eyeliner?
怎样才能让爸爸把眼线去掉呢？
Meet the emperor's grandson
认识皇帝的孙子
Please rest assured, Miss Gu
请顾小姐放心
it's natural
这是自然的
I'm going back
我要回去了
Think of a way
想想办法
Definitely not
当然不
Making Sun Jing's spy suspicious
让孙靖的间谍产生怀疑
Thank you, Emperor Sun
谢谢你，太阳皇帝
Miss Gu is too polite
顾小姐太客气了
I should be the one to thank Miss Gu
我该感谢顾小姐
Since the emperor's grandson entered the city
自从皇孙进城之后
But still safe
但还是安全的
We are all battle-hardened
我们都是身经百战的
Although the capital is surrounded by dangers,
尽管京城危机四伏，
But not sinister
但并不险恶
Then Wan Niang is relieved
这下万娘就放心了
Wan Niang has one more thing to ask for.
万娘还有一件事要请。
Please say
请说
Wan Niang is faking today
万娘今天装了
Come for incense
来上香
I heard that the sacred tree of Qingyun Temple is efficacious
听说青云寺的神树灵验
Break off a branch and soak it in the bath
折下一根树枝，浸泡在浴缸里
It can get rid of all diseases
它可以消除一切疾病
If you don't break a branch and take it back
如果你不折断树枝并把它收回来
I'm just afraid that the government's informants will be suspicious
只是怕政府的线人起疑
Could you please invite the emperor's grandson?
能请一下皇孙吗？
Come with me to pick a branch
跟我来摘枝吧
That's natural
那是自然的
Thank you, Emperor Sun
谢谢你，太阳皇帝
It is said that sincerity leads to wisdom
俗话说，真诚带来智慧
Before breaking the branches of the sacred tree
在折断圣树的树枝之前
You must make a wish sincerely
你必须真诚地许愿
Wish the person in your heart
祝愿你心里​​的那个人
safe and sound
安然无恙
Is it this branch?
是这个分行吗？
Or the branch next to it?
还是旁边的分行？
beside
旁
Thank you very much today
今天非常感谢
Thank you so much, Mr.
非常感谢您，先生。
No problem
没问题
Miss Gu
顾小姐
Just call me Shichiro from now on.
以后就叫我七郎吧。
Good Shi7ro
好石7ro
Jushichiro
十七郎
Although the sacred tree is spiritual
圣树虽然有灵性
But it’s discounted today
不过今天打折了
I’m going to take a bath today
我今天要洗澡
If you want to take it back
如果你想拿回来
To His Highness Prince Liang
致梁王殿下
I'm afraid it's a little too late.
恐怕有点太晚了。
The person I want to send to
我想发送给的人
right in this city
就在这个城市
They say this is outside the city
他们说这是城外
The sacred tree in Qingyun Temple is very spiritual
青云寺的神树很有灵性
I took a look
我看了一下
It turns out to be the Ping Po tree
原来是平婆树
Branches and leaves can indeed relieve pain and remove toxins
枝叶确实可以止痛排毒
I have already ordered the store
我已经到店下单了
I have prepared a large bucket of hot water for you
我给你准备了一大桶热水
Use it to soak in and bathe later
稍后用它浸泡和洗澡
Good for your arrow wounds
对你的箭伤有好处
You went outside the city
你去了城外
Gu Waanniang made an appointment with me
顾万娘跟我约好了
Meet at Qingyun Temple
相约青云寺
Said that Gu Mansion can leave now
说顾府现在可以离开了
But can't leave the city
但却无法离开这座城市
Moreover, there are eye spies all over the house and outside the house.
而且，屋内屋外到处都有眼探。
He always goes out now
他现在总是出去
Everyone will be followed
所有人都会被追随
So if we want to meet
所以如果我们想见面
You must think of a way
你必须想办法
I do
我愿意
I thought of a good way
我想到了一个好办法
There will be a good solution soon
很快就会有好的解决方案
That won't happen soon
这不会很快发生
come up with a way
想出一个办法
So that I can repay you for the kindness of breaking a branch.
好报答你折断树枝的恩情。
Unexpectedly, Li Yi
没想到，李毅
He really rescued his father
他真的救了他的父亲
Where now
现在在哪里
He took the capital from the east and supported Aoguan Pass.
东取都城，支援敖关。
It's even approaching Xichangjing
甚至已经快到西昌泾了
About to make a decision
即将做出决定
What an incredible achievement
多么令人难以置信的成就
Although we have lost the opportunity now
虽然现在我们已经失去了机会
But there is a way
但有一个办法
Can reverse disadvantages
可以扭转劣势
tell me the story
告诉我这个故事
Big brother
大哥
Father as the first emperor
父亲是第一位皇帝
The only remaining bloodline
仅存的血脉
It’s the king’s honor again
又是国王的荣耀
If it is from the father
如果是父亲的话
If you inherit the throne
如果你继承王位
That couldn't be more justified.
这再合理不过了。
If it is the father
如果是父亲的话
If you ascend the throne and become emperor in Dengdu,
若登位登都称帝，
Isn’t it true that there is no precedent in the country?
国内不是没有先例吗？
Who supported the father?
谁支持父亲？
When did you establish your father as king?
你什么时候立你父亲为王的？
That's far better than capturing Aoguan.
这比攻下敖关要好得多。
Retaking West Changjing is much more important
夺回西长泾更为重要
This is the merit of support
这就是支持的好处
Big brother
大哥
you are the eldest son
你是长子
Once my father ascends the throne,
当我的父亲登上王位后
You are a first-class hero
你是一流的英雄
Who else would you rather take the position of the East Palace?
你更愿意让谁来接替东宫的位置呢？
Furthermore
此外
Li Yi holds a heavy army
李毅手握重兵
He has repeatedly made military exploits
他屡立战功
But once my father ascends the throne,
但当我父亲登上王位后
His military exploits
他的军事功绩
It became a taboo in the DPRK
这在朝鲜已成为禁忌
Second brother, what do you say?
二哥，你说呢？
It really enlightened me
这确实让我大受启发
only
仅有的
My father is now in Auguan
我父亲现在在奥关
That Li Yi is full of tricks again
那李毅又是花样百出了
What if Li Yi
如果李毅呢
Don't let your father move to Luoyang
别让你爸爸搬到洛阳去
So what?
所以呢？
I still need to trouble my brother about this matter.
这件事我还得麻烦哥哥。
Go to Aoguan in person to welcome your father.
亲自去敖关迎接你的父亲。
My father loves big brother the most.
我的爸爸最疼爱哥哥。
If the elder brother goes there in person,
如果哥哥亲自去的话
Father must be happy to agree
父亲一定很高兴同意
If Li Yi blocks it,
如果李毅挡住的话，
Then he is unfaithful and unfilial
那么他就是不忠不孝
That makes sense
这就说得通了
This makes sense
这是有道理的
do not worry
不用担心
I will definitely remind my father in the future
我以后一定会提醒爸爸的
Make you a prince
让你成为王子
Big brother
大哥
The most urgent task now
现在最紧迫的任务
It’s to welcome my father back.
是为了迎接我父亲回来。
Will ascend the throne soon
即将登基
As for enfeoffment
至于分封
Don't be in a hurry
不要着急
I know brother means well
我知道哥哥是好意
only
仅有的
I'm afraid that others will hate me
我害怕别人会讨厌我
It's going to embarrass my elder brother
会让我哥哥难堪的
Second brother, are you sensible?
二哥，你懂事吗？
Met my sister-in-law
遇见了我的嫂子
Husband's second brother
丈夫的二弟
I ordered the kitchen to stew some soup
我吩咐厨房去炖点汤
You have had a busy day
你度过了忙碌的一天
Use more or less
使用或多或少
Thank you sister-in-law
谢谢嫂子
It's getting late
天色已晚
I won’t bother my brother and sister-in-law anymore.
我不会再打扰我的哥哥和嫂子了。
Use some
使用一些
My second brother chatted with you for a long time tonight
今晚二哥和你聊了很久
Did something happen?
发生了什么事吗？
there is nothing
没有什么
You don't have to worry too much
你不必太担心
It would be great if my third brother were here
如果我三哥在就好了
You three brothers
你们三兄弟
able to support each other
能够互相支持
Something's wrong
出了点问题
It can also be negotiated and measured
也可以协商和衡量
Your third brother is taller than your third brother.
你三哥比你三哥高。
You treat him as your brother
你把他当作你的兄弟
That's not necessarily what he thought
这不一定是他所想的
In fact, the third brother's heart
其实三哥的心
I have always respected you
我一直尊重你
this otherwise
否则这个
It is impossible to give up Luoyang
放弃洛阳是不可能的
He was willing
他愿意
Give up Luoyang?
放弃洛阳？
He is trying to rob Aoguan
他是想抢夺奥关
Just attacking west Changjing
刚攻西长靖
Look at him on the surface
看他表面的样子
A humble look
一副谦虚的样子
What is the reality?
现实是什么？
It’s about seizing military success everywhere.
这是为了在各地夺取军事成功。
It was when you first got married
那是你刚结婚的时候
I just took care of him for a few days.
我只是照顾了他几天而已。
Don't be deceived
不要被欺骗
Okay, okay, you go back first
好吧好吧，你先回去吧
I still have things to do
我还有事要做
Let's go back
我们回去吧
Jushichiro
十七郎
A message came from Aoguan
奥关传来消息
problem occurs
出现问题
What's wrong
怎么了
King of Linzi
临淄王
He brought the chariot himself
他亲自带来了战车
Picked up His Royal Highness Prince Liang from Aoguan
从奥关接梁亲王殿下
General Pei has no choice
裴将军别无选择
I had no choice but to send someone to deliver a letter.
没办法，只好派人送信。
My brother
我的兄弟
Really all the time
真的一直以来
all want to show
都想展示
His filial piety
他的孝心
Win, win, win
赢了，赢了，赢了
The mighty general
威武的将军
King Lin Er said
林儿王说道
This cricket is a once-in-a-hundred-year experience.
这场板球比赛是百年一遇的经历。
Come, come, come
怎样怎样怎样
Give you a cucumber to eat
给你一根黄瓜吃
What did you say about King Lin Er just now?
刚才你说林儿王怎么样了？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
King Lin Er
林儿王
Tell me about these days
说说这几天的事
I heard you didn't sleep well
听说你没睡好
Looking for famous doctors everywhere
到处寻找名医
He also asked Wu Guoshi
他还问吴国士
How to pray for you every day
每天如何为你祈祷
Jun'er, this kid
君儿这小子
Really thoughtful
真周到
Your Highness
殿下
Wu Guoshi said
Wu Guoshi said
Are you a person with the destiny of a true dragon?
你是拥有真龙命运的人吗？
The late emperor’s sons and grandsons
先帝的儿子和孙子
Only you can turn disaster into good fortune
只有你才能转祸为福
Turn danger into safety
化危险为安全
As soon as you ascend the throne
一旦登上王位
That traitor Sun Jing
孙靖那个叛徒
Will be defeated immediately
马上就会被打败
For the sake of the people of the world
为了世界人民
Your Highness, you must ascend the throne
殿下，您必须登基
That's right
这是正确的
For the people of the world
为了世界人民
I really should do this
我真的应该这样做
should do this
应该这样做
Why did you bring me here?
你为什么带我来这里？
This is the soy sauce garden
这就是酱油园
I was wronged when I was a child
小时候受过委屈
Or was beaten by his father
或者被父亲殴打
Will secretly
会偷偷地
Run here from the house
从家里跑到这里
Then hide in this tree
然后躲进这棵树里
While standing on this tree
当站在这棵树上时
Watching the sky high, clouds and white birds chirping
望天高云白鸟鸣
every summer
每个夏天
Cicadas will still emerge from their shells here
这里蝉仍会破壳而出
Leave an empty cicada shell behind
留下空蝉壳
I picked up the cicada shell
我捡起蝉壳
Paint with ink
用墨水作画
The result is just like a real cicada
结果就像真的蝉一样
Then I guess
那我猜
You must have used this as a false acknowledgment
您一定将此用作虚假确认
Go scare people
去吓唬人吧
yes
是的
Where is Li Jun?
李俊在哪里？
I'm most afraid of these insects.
我最怕这些昆虫。
once
一次
He knocked the ink onto the book
他把墨水碰到了书上
But he slandered me
但他却诽谤我
I was beaten by my father
我被我父亲打了
I can't be angry
我不能生气
I'll take that empty cicada shell
我要拿那空蝉壳
put it on his desk
把它放在他的桌子上
The results of it
其结果
Scared him so much that he screamed
把他吓得尖叫起来
alright
好吧
This time he went to complain again
这次他又去投诉了
I was beaten by my father again
我又被爸爸打了
In our Yingzhou
在我们瀛州
There is also a small hillside
还有一个小山坡
behind the woods
在树林后面
spring time
春天的时候
The hillside is full of wild flowers
山坡上开满了野花
When I was little I used to lead horses
我小时候常常牵马
lying on the hillside
躺在山坡上
looking at the clouds in the sky
看着天上的云彩
drifting slowly
慢慢地漂流
If I were a child
如果我是个孩子
It would be nice to know you
很高兴认识你
Not always
不总是
Maybe when I was a kid
也许当我还是个孩子的时候
Do you still find me annoying?
你还觉得我烦吗？
When you first met me
当你第一次见到我时
You still hate me
你还是恨我
I hate it so much that my teeth itch
我恨得牙痒痒
How bad were you then?
那时的你有多糟糕？
Kick me into the well
把我踢进井里
It made me soak in cold water for a long time
让我在冷水里泡了好久
Then you still treat me
那你还是对我
Kicked into the river
被踢进河里
Then do I want it now?
那我现在想要吗？
I'll give you a couple of slaps to vent your anger.
我就打你几巴掌，以泄你的愤怒。
Bring your face closer
把脸靠近一点
You said you can't play but can't play
你说你不能玩却不能玩
Why can I only shoot but not play?
为什么我只能射击不能玩？
I do not care
我不在乎
you played me
你玩弄了我
I'm about to bounce back
我即将反弹
look
看
I let you play
我让你玩
Miss
错过
Qiucui
Qiucui
I finally saw you
我终于见到你了
Why are you back?
你怎么回来了？
I'm not asking you to stay in Aoguan
我不是要你留在奥关
Are you taking care of His Highness Prince Liang?
你在照顾梁王殿下吗？
His Royal Highness the King of Liang
梁王殿下
Was taken to Luoyang
被带到洛阳
What kind of king is Lin?
林氏是一个怎样的王？
He is the son of His Highness Prince Liang
他是梁亲王殿下的儿子
He personally brought troops and horses
他亲自带来了兵马
Picked up at Aoguan
在奥关领取
King Lin Er
林儿王
Picked up His Royal Highness Prince Liang
接了梁亲王殿下
It’s King Lin Er
是林儿王
Just afraid
只是害怕
This storm is coming again
这场风暴又来了
Why is he so troubled?
他为何如此烦恼？
Miss, you have already gone home
小姐，你已经回家了
This incense burner is so exquisite
这香炉好精致
That was sent by my father
这是我父亲寄来的
master
掌握
The master is so kind to the lady
主人对这位女士真是太好了
Na Fuzhong
Na Fuzhong
No one will dare to look down on the young lady anymore.
再也没有人敢小看这位小姐了。
for father
为父亲
a useful daughter
一个有用的女儿
She is a good daughter
她是一个好女儿
We have discussed it with Mr. Gu
我们已经跟顾先生商量过了
I'll ask Miss Gu tomorrow
我明天去问问顾小姐
Accompany the Prime Minister out of the house
陪同总理走出家门
Let Mr. Gu just pretend to go to the silk shop
让顾先生假装去丝绸店
tailor-made
量身定做
Our store has various kinds of silk and satin
本店有各种丝缎
For your choice
供您选择
Please come inside
请进来
Pillar
支柱
Greeting guests
迎接客人
Let me help you measure the size
让我帮你测量一下尺寸
My father doesn’t like to be touched by outsiders.
我父亲不喜欢被外人碰触。
It's better for me to measure my father's body.
我还是给父亲量一下身体比较好。
good
好的
two persons
两个人
Please come here for measuring.
请到这里来测量。
Mr. Gu entered the interior
顾先生进入室内
Behind the screen, blocking everyone’s view
屏幕后面，挡住了所有人的视线
Start measuring
开始测量
My Cui Jiajun is in Beijing
My Cui Jiajun is in Beijing
An old acquaintance, Koushiro
老相识 小四郎
Best at ventriloquism
最擅长腹语
Let him pretend to be Gu Xiang
让他冒充顾湘
and Gu Waanniang’s voice
还有顾万娘的声音？？？
What's in this store?
这家店里有什么？
Sober and varied materials
清醒而多样的材料
Look
看
Pick something up for your mother too
也给你妈妈挑点东西
Father
父亲
I think this is pretty good
我认为这很好
But this treasure pattern
但这宝纹
Seems a bit too old-fashioned
似乎有点太老套了
Father
父亲
Take a look at this
看看这个
This can be used as a robe
这个可以当长袍用
very good very good
非常好非常好
Then let’s choose this one.
那么我们就选择这个吧。